Tristan Bates

103-25 Ritchie Ave Toronto, ON, M6R 2J6

647-500-4723

tristan@bluemage.ca

https://www.bluemage.ca

Profile

Software engineer with 15 years professional experience specializing in highly available systems, performance optimization and DevOps best practices. I am looking for leadership opportunities with innovative startups where I can help guide technical decisions and solve interesting problems.

Experience

Senior Site Reliability Engineer, PagerDuty; Toronto, ON - 2018-Current

- Established and led the Kubernetes Working Group, a cross-engineering initiative to determine feasibility and roadmap of a migration to Kubernetes
- Modified platform infrastructure to improve performance and reliability and significantly reduce operational costs
- · Led migration of hundreds of services to modern CI/CD tooling
- Wrote Terraform modules for commonly used resources that encapsulated company's best practices and compliance/security requirements
- Acted as SME on cross-team collaborative effort to containerize legacy monolith and migrate from legacy infrastructure to current container orchestrator
- Led technical evaluation of product for acquisition consideration

DevOps Engineer, Top Hat; Toronto, ON - 2017-2018

- · Automated multi-region deploy pipelines
- Migrated application infrastructure from legacy data centre to AWS
- Introduced reverse proxy for routing requests to backend microservices
- · Created tooling for rapid microservice development
- Responsible for three nines uptime including on call response
- · Day-to-day on premise consulting and support for the rest of the engineering department

DevOps Engineer, Fullscreen Direct; Toronto, ON - 2013-2016

- Helped grow startup that was acquired
- · Managed HA services and administered haproxy, apache, mysql, elasticsearch and more
- Conducted load, performance and service failure testing to determine bottle necks and points of weakness
- Responsible for administration and security of servers and infrastructure
- · Created build and deploy pipelines for development, staging and production environments
- Planned and executed migration of infrastructure to AWS
- Migrated legacy PHP code base to custom MVC framework built using Symfony 3 components

Senior Software Engineer, Parka Group; Toronto, ON - 2006-2013

- Hired and trained new employees as team lead and helped organize the team's work load
- Responsible for high level architecture, optimization and scaling
- · Setup continuous integration and automated testing systems
- Implemented version control, build and deploy processes
- Introduced agile to the company and helped form requirements gathering process
- Created custom MVC framework to replace difficult to work with legacy code

Education

Ryerson University - Toronto, ON - Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, 2006